Heraklion, Crete, Greece Open to relocation ammarkov@gmail.com

Ammar Qammaz

Software / Research / Computer Vision / Robotics / Al

ammar.gr github.com/AmmarkoV/ linkedin.com/ammarkov/

Highly experienced software engineer with 15+ years of experience in C / C++, 9+ years specializing on Computer Vision as member of the Computer Vision and Robotics Laboratory of the Foundation of Research and Technology of Greece. **Areas of expertise:** Computer vision, 3D pose estimation, artificial neural networks, real-time computing, robotics, HCI. **Impact:** Among the top 50 most active Github developers in Greece, Author of MocapNET, 265+ citations, in charge of the human perception stack of the EU FP7 Hobbit robot, a.k.a. first robot trials in houses of elderly people in human history, GNU/Linux enthusiast with various open-source contributions.

PROJECTS

AUTO-MNET, BonsApps (EU H2020 Grant no.101015848) AI Talent grant (Winner No. Bons_1OC_20)

2022 - Present

• Technical lead, providing an embedded 3D real-time driver body pose estimation framework for cars to ensure safe driving.

I.C.HUMANS, HFRI (ΕΛΙΔΕΚ Proj. No. 91)

2021 - 2022

• Unobtrusive capturing of human motion articulation and semantics.

Mingei, EU H2020 grant no. 822336

2018 - 2020

• 3D pose estimation from RGB videos of experts performing various historically important procedures for cultural preservation

Co4Robots, EU H2020-ICT-2016-1-73186

2017 - 2019

Preparing deliverables, experiments on real-time RGB human perception on the ROS platform

Remote Acceleration service for low-Power Integrated systems and Devices (RAPID), EU H2020-ICT-644312

2015 - 2017

• 3D hand tracking from RGBD using heterogeneous computing for low-power integrated systems and devices

Hobbit The Mutual Care Robot, EU FP7-ICT-288146

2013 - 2015

• In charge of implementing the RGBD human perception stack of the Robot, emergency user fall detection, system design/tuning, web interface using my embedded AmmarServer, review meeting demos and on-site support on live trials.

Robohow.cog, EU FP7-ICT-288533

2013 — 2015

• Integration of FORTH 3D Hand Pose estimation and 3D Object Tracking framework with ROS and the PR2 robot, Work on force sensing based on vision (See CVPR '15 Publication), 3D tracking performance improvements (See BMVC '15 Publication).

GuarddoG Robot Project, BSc Thesis

2008 - 2012

Software and hardware for a small autonomous wheeled robot for domestic security and surveillance designed from scratch.

EXPERIENCE

PhD Graduate Research Assistant

Jan 2019 — Present

Computer Vision and Robotics Lab, Institute of Computer Science, Foundation of Research and Technology

Heraklion

- Involvement in I.C.HUMANS, SustAGE, Mingei Projects and BonsAPPs 1st Support program.
- Created MocapNET and Hierarchical Coordinate Descent algorithm for real-time 3D body and hand pose estimation from RGB.

MSc Graduate Research Assistant

Jan 2015 — Jan 2019

Computer Vision and Robotics Lab, Institute of Computer Science, Foundation of Research and Technology

Heraklion

- Involvement in Co4Robots, RAMCIP and RAPID Projects
- 3D Human pose estimation from RGBD video using a 3D reconstruction of the subject. 3D Hand Tracking and Gesture recognition.

Software Research Engineer

Jan 2013 — Jan 2015

Computer Vision and Robotics Lab, Institute of Computer Science, Foundation of Research and Technology

Heraklion

- Involvement in Hobbit, Robohow.cog Projects
- Model based 3D Hand and Object Pose Estimation from RGBD, developed RGBDAcquisition a framework for 3D data acquisition.

Communication systems operator

Nov 2010 — Aug 2011

Hellenic Army

• Served as a communication systems operator on the HNDGS-NATO headquarters handling classified signals and state secrets.

Freelancer Oct 2005 — Nov 2010

- Developed, hosted and maintained e-commerce platforms for car dealerships, jewellery stores, and small businesses.
- Authored database software for medical clinics and dentists, still being used today.
- Developed shareware and freeware mini-games and utilities for windows PCs.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy, Computational and Cognitive Vision and Robotics, University of Crete **Master of Science, Computational and Cognitive Vision and Robotics,** University of Crete, GPA: 8.86/10.00 **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science,** Athens University of Business and Economics, GPA: 6.51/10.00

Jan 2019 — Present Oct 2015 — Nov 2018 Sep 2004 — Sep 2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

Platforms

C, C++, Python, Shell scripting(BASH, Csh, Perl), Java, PHP, SQL, Matlab/Octave, FreePascal

GNU/Linux, Android, Windows, Embedded (ATMEL, AVR, ESP, Arduino)

OpenCV, OpenGL, GLSL, CUDA, PThreads, ROS, PCL, Tensorflow, Keras, NumPy, Git, WxWidgets

Computer Vision, Image Processing, Computer Graphics, Robotics, HCI, Deep Neural Networks, Machine

Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Embedded/Ubiquitous Computing

PUBLICATIONS

Frameworks
Research Interests

- 1. Hauser, H. *et al.* Multimodal Narratives for the Presentation of Silk Heritage in the Museum. *Heritage* **5**, 461–487. ISSN: 2571-9408. https://www.mdpi.com/2571-9408/5/1/27 (2022).
- 2. Qammaz, A. & Argyros, A. A. Towards Holistic Real-time Human 3D Pose Estimation using MocapNETs in British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC 2021) (BMVA, Nov. 2021).
- 3. Qammaz, A. & Argyros, A. Occlusion-tolerant and personalized 3D human pose estimation in RGB images in 2020 25th International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR) (2021), 6904–6911.
- 4. Zabulis, X. *et al.* Representation and Preservation of Heritage Crafts. *Sustainability* **12.** ISSN: 2071-1050. https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/12/4/1461 (2020).
- 5. Bajones, M. et al. Results of field trials with a Mobile service robot for older adults in 16 private households. ACM Transactions on Human-Robot Interaction (THRI) 9, 1–27 (2019).
- 6. Qammaz, A. & Argyros, A. A. MocapNET: Ensemble of SNN Encoders for 3D Human Pose Estimation in RGB Images. in BMVC (2019).
- 7. Qammaz, A. et al. On the Feasibility of Real-Time 3D Hand Tracking using Edge GPGPU Acceleration. arXiv preprint arXiv:1804.11256 (2018).
- 8. Bajones, M. et al. Hobbit: providing fall detection and prevention for the elderly in the real world. Journal of Robotics (2018).
- 9. Qammaz, A., Michel, D. & Argyros, A. A hybrid method for 3d pose estimation of personalized human body models in 2018 IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV) (2018), 456–465.
- 10. Michel, D., Qammaz, A. & Argyros, A. A. Markerless 3d human pose estimation and tracking based on rgbd cameras: an experimental evaluation in Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on PErvasive Technologies Related to Assistive Environments (2017), 115–122.
- 11. Foukarakis, M. et al. A Robot-based Application for Physical Exercise Training. in ICT4AgeingWell (2016), 45-52.
- 12. Kyriazis, N. et al. in Man-Machine Interactions 4 19-28 (Springer, 2016).
- 13. Pham, T.-H. et al. Capturing and reproducing hand-object interactions through vision-based force sensing in Object Understanding for Interaction (2015).
- 14. Qammaz, A., Kyriazis, N. & Argyros, A. A. Boosting the Performance of Model-based 3D Tracking by Employing Low Level Motion Cues. in BMVC (2015), 144–1.
- 15. Pham, T.-H. et al. Towards force sensing from vision: Observing hand-object interactions to infer manipulation forces in Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition (2015), 2810–2819.

AWARDS & HONORS

2003 Chosen for International Olympiad of Informatics 2004 Greek team after national programming contest

2008 Robotics, best of Show Award for GuarddoG project in the Athens Digital Week

2022 PhD work on MocapNET awarded a BonsApps (EU H2020 no.101015848) Al Talent grant (Winner No. Bons_10C_20)

NATIONALITY, LANGUAGES, OTHER INFORMATION & INTERESTS

European/Greek Nationality, Natively speak Greek. English FCE, CPE Cambridge diplomas. Rudimentary knowledge of German. I have an INTJ Myers-Briggs personality type indicator and O+ blood type. In my spare time I tweak my custom built Quadcopter, maintain my open source repositories, game, watch documentaries, amateur photography, sailing, latin dance and travel.

LINKS

E-Mail: ammarkov@gmail.com, WWW: http://ammar.gr/, Github: https://github.com/AmmarkoV/, YouTube: http://www.youtube.com/user/ammarkov, HackerRank: https://www.hackerrank.com/ammarkov, Linked-In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ammarkov, Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/ammarkov1/